Carolyn Vasisko

Portfolio: http://www.vasisko.com Email: carolyn.vasisko@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/carolyn-vasisko Phone: 832.247.0518 Github: https://github.com/vasisko Located: Cypress, Texas

Full stack web developer with diverse background including 15 years of project management and 10 years of front end coding (HTML and CSS). Dedicated team member effectively collaborates with others. Adept at learning new technologies. Creative problem solver driven by challenges.

Skills:

HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Materialize, Responsive Design, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Handlebars.js, React.js, Git and Heroku

Current Projects:

StockMarketPets.com: Full Stack Class Project, http://stockmarketpets.com

Web application that allows players to adopt a pet while learning the basics of playing the stock market.

- Member of the portfolio feature team. Responsible for front end development of data visualization components including stock ticker, pie chart, and pet status bars, used on feature page as well as sitewide.
- React, Node.js, Git

W.I.N. Houston: Full Stack Group Project, *https://git.heroku.com/young-coast-31457.git* Web application for connecting women in need (W.I.N.)/in crisis in Houston with local resources on the front end, while developing a network of resources created by the app's members on the backend.

- Defined project parameters and structure. Personally involved in all aspects of backend development including developing the beginnings of a member dashboard and leading efforts to successfully incorporate an authenticated login feature
- Node.js, Express, Handlebars, Sequelize, JavaScript/JQuery, Passport and Bcryptjs, Git and Heroku

My Veggie Eats: Front End Group Project, https://vasisko.github.io/MyVeggieEats
Web application for vegetarians to search for nearby dining options with personalized hot spots and dining notes

- Collaborated with team using Trello and Git to manage project tasks and files. Personally responsible for wireframe, front end design and coding, and mobile responsiveness
- Mockflow, HTML, CSS, and Materialize

Professional Experience

Cy-Fair ISD and Katy ISD, 2008 – 2017

Math Teacher

- Optimized course materials and streamlined instruction
- Continually analyzed student scores and adjusted instruction to maximize success and meet increased rigor of standardized tests.
- Set-up and operated a lunch-hour drop-in tutoring lab.
- Designed and developed math boot camp for at-risk students for campus.
- Interacted with students, parents, team, department, school administration and district support staff.

MotherMedia LLC, 1998 – 2008

Front End Web Developer

- Owned and operated web development company
- Responsible for front end programming(HTML/CSS/CGI) and project management from start of creative design, through development, and on to test, launch, and maintenance
- Coordinated efforts of team of freelancers, prioritizing and delegating responsibilities to meet the project requirements
- Helped small businesses evaluate their needs to efficiently and effectively establish their online presence

Tyree Environmental Technologies, 1993 – 1996

Project Engineer

- Functioned as liaison to Mobil Oil Corporation for construction of new/redesigned/upgraded service stations
- Coordinated efforts of team of architects, engineers, subcontractors, and service station managers to effectively meet project milestones and maintain project schedules
- Interfaced with town officials to obtain necessary project approvals and permits in expeditious manner

Hughes Electronics Corporation, 1987 – 1993

Mechanical Engineer

- Collaborated with team to design, test and build mechanical support mount for optics measuring station, and functioned as liaison to oversee contractor to successfully secure fabrication of optics
- Maintained project schedule and reported status to NASA
- Conducted thermal analysis of various aerospace components

Education:

The University of Texas at Austin – Center for Professional Education in Houston, Houston, TX The Houston Coding Boot Camp – Full Stack Flex Program, Certificate, July 2018

Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Troy, NY

BS, Mechanical Engineering